Who can tell me another colour
other than red and black...
What other colour can you see?
Silver
So we have red black white silver...
Idiot!
Get out of the way!
"DAHAI - AMATEUR TAILOR"
Everyone queue up!
Don't push!
You'll all get on board!
Hey!
"XING'ER - HANDYWOMAN -
CATCHPHRASE: I AM USEFUL"
What are you doing here?
Why can't you stop being so troublesome?
"ROB THE TRAIN"
You! Get up!
You never take me on the big missions.
If only we had big missions in the first place!
I am Feng Banxian magician of the snake box!
"BANXIAN - FORTUNE TELLER - CATCHPHRASE:
MYSTERIES MUST NOT BE REVEALED"
Inside the box there is a snake.
Do you believe me?
Just you?
I just snatched it from outside the train
in the blink of an eye!
Wow!
"MA YUAN - HEAD PORTER -
CATCHPHRASE: SHUT UP!"
"XIAOHU - PORTER -
CATCHPHRASE: LET'S GO!"
"RUI - MAINTENANCE WORKER -
CATCHPHRASE: OUR PEOPLE?"
"DAKUI - MAINTENANCE WORKER -
CATCHPHRASE: WHAT NOW?"
Turn around.
Turn around!
Stop!
Ya! Me! Te?!
Your dad!
You Chinese?
Uh...Hai!
Speak Chinese!
Chinese?
I'll give you two choices.
One: I knock you out with this.
Or two: you pretend to be knocked out.
I said pretend! Pretend!
Not to actually do it!
What are you doing? Let me go!
You bastard!
What are you doing?!
What?
And so you see I've made the creature
disappear in an instant!
Look an empty box!
In the blink of an eye! Wow!
That's how fast I am!
(imitating Japanese) A big sack of potatoes!
Sit down!
Turn around.
Turn around!
Who brought you?
Aaaaah! Snake! Why is it back again?!
That's just my little magic trick don't worry.
Hey brother
Do me a favor and strip him down.
Hey brother I didn't know you spoke Japanese!
(imitating Japanese) Where do you dig up potatoes?
Where do you dig up potatoes?
Go dig in the mountains.
Dig up a sack of potatoes a sack of potatoes.
Where do you dig up potatoes?
Go dig in the mountains.
Dig dig dig! Dig up a sack of potatoes.
Dig up a sack of potatoes. Hai!
Where do you dig up potatoes huh?
A sack of potatoes...!
That's the head...
The ear...
The eyes...
The tail.
These are the wings.
This is a flying tiger.
Draw it just like that! Alright!
Whoa that's a big fire.
This way.
"The evening sun is setting in the west"
"In the west...
Weishan Lake is peaceful and still"
"I will go play my Chinese lute"
"Singing a peaceful and lulling tune"
"The road is leading me all the way back home"
"My home sits on Mount Liang Liang Liang"
Begin!
"YAMAGUCHI -
CAPTAIN JAPANESE MILITARY POLICE"
Captain! Phone call for you.
- Hello?
- Candied fruit!
Get your candied fruit!
Yes sir.
"SASAKI - STATION MASTER"
Sir. Please come and take a look.
Get ready to deploy!
Deploy! Time to move out!
"SAKAMOTO - TRANSLATOR"
There's a problem.
"HUANG YIFENG DEPUTY STATION MASTER"
Stop nagging! Fine! Fine!
Be careful. Steady!
Give me another one!
Yuan! Yuan!
Hey! What are you doing?
"AUNTIE QIN - PANCAKE SELLER"
It's delicious!
Yuan do you want pancakes?
Yes!
I don't have enough for all of you!
Eat them while they're hot!
The ones on top are good.
Share them amongst yourselves.
I saw the Station Master.
I think something's wrong.
It's fine. This is delicious!
Get off the train! Now!
Something's not right.
Why are you smiling?
- I'm not sir.
- Yes you are!
Hey Xing'er!
"SAN LAIZI - THIEF"
Get lost! Why are you everywhere we go?
I'm sorry!
You don't have to look away.
Why can't you act serious for once!
It's that winged cat again.
Who did this?
- I didn't do it!
- Who are you?
What is your occupation?
I'm just a tailor!
Prove it!
What do you have to prove it?!
Wait! Relax!
A tailor!
He wasn't the one...
Stay back! You are not to leave the train!
Good... morning! Have you... eaten... yet?
This person is really amazing!
He can make things disappear in a flash!
Yes!
Take him away.
Wait!
What did you say?!
You're scaring me!
Who did this to you?
Answer me!
Don't look.
Brother what now?
It's fine. Just don't run.
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Hey! Don't shoot!
Sorry.
Go get the duty logbook.
Yes sir!
Sir! Captain! Commander!
What have we done wrong?
I'm sorry.
I'm the foreman here.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
Sir don't hit him!
Don't hit anyone!
It hurts!
The duty logbook sir!
What's his name?
What's your name?
I'm Ma Yuan.
He signed in this morning.
So did everyone else.
We've been here since dawn.
That's right we were all here!
You alright?
I'm fine I'm fine.
Brother.
In a few days go hide these clothes.
Brother we have guns that we can't fire
and clothes that we can't wear.
So why do we keep them?
For a big fire?
Today if it wasn't for Brother Ma
you'd be in the hands of the Japanese!
And you? If you'd aimed better with that crate...
You're one to talk!
I said to get on the passenger car
not the cargo!
So what? Hey careful!
When can we do something really big?
Shut up!
Brother you don't even smoke.
So why do you always carry that pipe?
There's no reason.
How do I draw the flying tiger?
I couldn't get it right today.
What is that?
Where the hell are they?!
The captain wants to know where they are!
Let... let me consult the deities!
O heavenly spirits! Spirits of the earth!
Please appear before me!
Looks like something big will happen today.
He says something big will happen today.
Hahahaha!
Hello?
Something major is going down!
Let's go see what's happening. Dahai!
Are you going to go eat pancakes Brother?
See you at the noodle shop Brother.
Okay.
You don't have to see me off. Really!
Lock him up!
I'll let myself out! I'm not going that way!
"RESCUE THE INJURED SOLDIER"
Hey Ma Yuan. Visiting Auntie Qin again?
Shut up!
Mom I'm home!
The pancake smells great!
Dahai help me out!
I'm bleeding again.
What's wrong? Come sit down!
What's wrong with the donkey?
It kicked me so I drugged it.
To let it calm down a little.
Such bad luck today!
Beaten by the Japanese in the daytime.
I was beaten by the Japanese too.
Well did a donkey kick you at night?
Well no...
I'm so unlucky!
You are pretty unlucky.
Have some pancakes!
I thought you were all just messing around.
But now you've stirred up so much trouble!
It's nothing big Mom. Right Brother?
Dad I want to join the small missions too!
Hey something's not right.
Dahai you call me Brother and call her Mom.
But what if one day I marry her?
Would you call me Brother or Dad?
Oh come on!
Xing'er what about you?
Would you still call me Dad or...
What are you blabbering on about...
It's become serious. You always tell people
to shut up but you talk the most!
Maybe one day I'll drug you too!
Just put some in the pancakes.
The more the better.
You think I won't do it?
You should mark the drugged one
so you don't eat it yourself.
You really think I won't do it?
"DAGUO - EIGHTH ROUTE ARMY SOLDIER"
May I hide out here?
Sorry I'll go elsewhere then.
Get in there!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Get him out.
Search thoroughly.
You again!
Why is it you again?
Someone went over the wall!
You see I'm a widow!
It would create gossip if he was seen here.
So he had to sneak in.
Sneakin?
That's right he snuck in over the wall
You've forgotten? You.
You. This morning. Hit me.
Blood. Pain.
So you snuck in.
Right just sneaking around!
Captain!
We've found someone suspicious.
No wonder we're always
losing things in the cellar!
You've been stealing from me!
Get him out of here!
I'm only borrowing!
Hicks!
Next house!
He's on fire!
Get water! What do we do?
Are you okay? Say something!
Hurry!
I'm okay! The fire's out!
Everyone else was killed by the Japanese.
They all died but he alone survived?
Is he a deserter?
I doubt it.
Where have you hidden him?
At Auntie Qin's. They're taking care of him.
We'll move him to the cave later.
Fan Chuan. Back so late?
"FAN CHUAN - NOODLE SHOP OWNER"
Where have you been off having fun this time?
Hey kid... Yes Boss?
Go feed the horse.
Sure.
- Make sure it eats its fill.
- Alright.
That's a nice jacket!
I hate this kind of person.
Try giving that attitude to the Japanese!
He really did fight the Japanese.
I hear he's a sharpshooter.
Whatever. Why did the Chinese army
want to blow up the bridge?
He didn't tell me.
I don't get it.
They sacrificed all those men
to blow up our own bridge?
The Japanese are occupying it
so it's their bridge. Get it?
How dare they! It's our home turf!
Take it outside.
Stop screaming about the Japanese here.
What do you mean?
You heard me. All you guys do is talk!
Yet you can't do anything big!
How do you know
we haven't already done something big?
Let's go!
Exactly today we...
That's all you guys can do.
At least we're not cowards like you Fan Chuan.
What'd you say?
Actually Fan Chuan is right. Bill please!
Zhu let's go.
Have you heard?
Fan Chuan was a warlord's bodyguard!
Ma Yuan! Get down here!
What's up?
Listen stop causing trouble for me okay?
Just one more job. And then we're done.
Don't push me. Don't force me to rat you out.
"YUKO-
INSPECTOR JAPANESE MILITARY POLICE"
Welcome Madam.
What?
Banzai!
Bonfire?
What're they saying?
It's Japanese!
Long live!
Banzai!
Why're there so many soldiers?
They must be reinforcements for the bridge.
I'm feeling much better. Can I leave now?
This injury will take
at least ten more days to heal.
Ten days?!
If I don't blow the bridge in four days...
Then what?
You wouldn't understand!
Just pretend we've never met.
And let me go okay?
I don't want to fight anymore! I miss home!
I miss Mom!
Alright alright! I can't stand crying!
I miss my mom too!
She was also killed by the Japanese!
I didn't even get to see her one last time!
Alright. Stop crying!
I can't stop you. Just leave!
How do I leave?
How would he leave?
By train.
The train is here!
Get ready! Let's go!
Don't be scared.
Lower us!
Thanks. You guys can go.
Dahai you go first.
Go ahead.
It is going to snow... Let me send you off.
It's not easy to be a soldier.
When you get home...
Brother I was lying
when I said I was going home.
I'm actually going back to the troops.
That bridge must be blown up.
Tell me why do you have to blow up the bridge?
It's for the war effort.
You wouldn't understand.
People like you can't do such big tasks right?
Fine. Your leg injury isn't that bad.
Get off the train when it stops.
I think it's stopping.
The Japanese are inspecting the train. Run!
I told you to leave! Now we're both stuck!
Don't worry there are plenty
of places to hide. Hurry!
They're here for me.
I'll deal with them.
Leave! It's an order!
- One more favor!
- Go ahead!
Search thoroughly!
If I don't make it
find my platoon.
Tell them that I failed.
And tell them to blow the bridge in three days.
Also I'm not a deserter.
Of course not. Where's your platoon?
Search up there!
Hurry there's no time!
Remember what I said.
The bridge must be destroyed!
What's up? Brother?
Come and see!
Off on another big mission Brother?
"ERPANG - BLACKSMITH"
Dad that soldier from the Eighth Route Army...
He should be home by now right?
What do we do now?
Yeah tell us what to do.
I'm skipping work today.
I'm going to your mother's grave.
Don't worry.
Although we have reinforcements
we should remain cautious.
If even the Eighth Route Army
couldn't blow up the bridge
then...
can anyone else do it?
You kept saying
I'm incapable of doing anything big.
In a few days I'll show you what I can do.
Maybe I can finally avenge you.
For real.
What are you doing?
We're doing whatever you're doing Brother!
- Let's go!
- Dad
I know... Shut up!
Don't tell me you're going to blow up that bridge!
You're right I'm going to blow it up.
See? I told you so!
We're going to do something big!
Let's do it then!
But if the entire Eighth Route Army couldn't do it
can people like us do it?
Him? Him? And Me? How can we!
Did I say that we're doing it together?
We're a team!
We always do everything as one!
We eat together we... Quiet!
I was going to ask you guys to join me.
I can't get the soldier's message
to the Eighth Route Army.
So we have to do this for them.
That's great! Let's do it!
Hold on! Don't you know
how many explosives we need for that?
I know where we can find some!
In the armory at Shagou Station!
Station Master Huang mumbled something
while I was fitting him.
He said there's a load of explosive packs.
Let's do it. We'll do it tomorrow!
Let's go!
How do we blow a bridge with explosive packs?
Easy. We just throw the packs at the bridge.
Duang! Duang! It explodes!
Duang?
"GETTING EXPLOSIVES"
Fan Chuan.
Here. Noodles coming up!
I asked for an large bowl with extra meat!
Can you afford it?
I stole money from the Japanese!
Hey Fan Chuan.
What's up?
You've fought in the war right?
How'd you detonate a Japanese explosive pack?
Just throw it. Throw it!
Throw it. Throw it!
That will never work.
Oh. Then...
Figure it out yourself.
Listen. We can't beat the Japanese.
I fought for a warlord.
That's pretty awesome right?
And we still lost!
With so few of you
don't even bother!
Count me in Brother. I'm not a coward!
Dahai I want to join your next big mission.
Something's bothering you inside.
You can't even hide it.
About us...
when are we going to get hitched?
Later. Wait a little longer.
Hey get out of here
Hurry up!
He's hitting me!
Here!
Go!
Hey there's a ladder over here.
That's mine! I'm giving you a duck sir!
Give me back my duck!
A duck for you sir!
Hey what are you doing?
What do we do?
You go up.
How?
Drop two packs.
Why did you drop them all?
How else would you be able to get up here?
There's one left.
Let's take it.
Cigarettes! Get your cigarettes!
(Japanese)
All that work and you stole just one pack?!
You try it then!
If I was there...
Forget it. You can't even climb up
to the roof Shut up!
Assembly! Go chase the train!
You over there!
Go check it out.
So many Japanese soldiers!
Don't worry. We're safe here.
Not safe.
Are they here for us?
You take the explosives.
You three to the front.
Let's go.
I'll go first. You guys follow me.
Okay!
You. You go first!
What do we do now?
How would I know!
The explosives!
Hurry!
Hey there's flour here!
Let's go!
Bastards!
Okay we're done!
Be careful!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Where'd you go?
Hey!
How do you use these explosives?
Just light it up.
Go go go!
Hide Dakui!
Nice flour.
I can make Brother some buns tonight.
Put that down!
Where is he?
That's a really big explosion!
That was close.
Soon we'll be the rulers of this place.
What do you mean?
The battle in China is growing.
In a few days we'll have an unending chain
of supplies to the front line.
Did something unusual happen today?
Did anyone miss work today?
Did anyone miss work?
There are no cargo trucks today
so there are not many people...
Why are you smiling?
I'm sorry.
Kameda you're responsible
for the lost explosives.
What the heck is this?
This is the only thing I could find!
Let's start!
This is going to hurt.
Don't be a coward!
My hand!
It hurts!
Imbecile!
We can't blow up the bridge!
Why not?
It's rare we get to do something so big.
Don't you want revenge?
Of course I want revenge!
But blowing up the bridge isn't revenge!
- Yes it is revenge!
- Stop!
First the Japanese know
their explosives have been stolen.
They're out for blood so we must be careful.
Second if they know
the explosives were meant for blowing up the bridge
it'll make it more difficult to do
so in the end. Third...
So what?
We just let Daguo and the soldiers die in vain?!
In vain?!
What's the third thing?
What?
The third thing!
I forgot.
Come here!
What's going on?
Erpang's butcher knife!
Knives rods chains. All solid.
Come take a look at this!
I'll kick! Go!
Come on!
Go away!
- Get off me!
- It's okay.
They are not local!
Are you okay?
I'll kill you with spice!
Go!
There are many Japanese soldiers over there!
Brother run!
Stop. Don't move!
Keep searching!
We've found him! That's him!
Arrest them.
That looks painful. What'll we do?
Can we get through this without any pain?
I hope so.
Let's give it try.
You two look alike.
He says you two look quite alike.
Alike!
What I want to know is... Alike?
I'm much more handsome!
You're more handsome?
I was more handsome than you
when I was your age.
Did you see me when I was young?
Of course not.
How is that possible?
Wasn't that decades ago?
I wiped your butt when you were little!
What do you think?
Look at his nose!
What's wrong with my nose?
It's too big!
What's wrong with having a big nose?
Yours is too small!
A big nostril collects dirt easily!
- A tiny nose can hardly breathe!
- Shut up!
What'd they say?
Noses...
Noses?!
Stop babbling!
I don't understand.
Get a Chinese person Captain.
We don't understand him.
We...Don't...Understand...
What are they saying?
They got themselves in trouble.
My dad says you're an amazing sharpshooter!
Please help him!
I'm not a sharpshooter.
Look at these!
Do they look like they can shoot?
They do!
If I was a sharpshooter then why would I be here?
I'd be doing big things with my life.
The Tigers are doing big things!
Well I have a little business to take care of.
Get someone else.
Go! Go!
What if they won't talk?
Are you Chinese?
Hi...
Speak Chinese
We have a saying in Chinese...
"A wise man doesn't join a hopeless fight."
Exactly! Since you know what I mean...
Shut up!
You don't want to get beat up
by the Japanese right?
Of course not.
Good to know. So...
Hey tell them...
That's all I can do to help you.
Well... they've revealed everything.
They admit that...
They stole the explosives.
They admit to stealing the explosives.
Why?
To fry fish! Frying fish with explosives!
They fry fish with explosives.
Why?
To make them more crispy and delicious!
There's a saying...
"Every movement needs a pioneer."
"Different lands have different customs!"
"You'd be lost everywhere
if you didn't go anywhere."
Translate!
I'm sorry!
I'm so sorry!
It's not my fault that you don't get it.
Why hit me?
Let's go!
All day you keep saying "let's go"
but why didn't you do any reconnaissance?
Stop arguing!
Arguing doesn't solve a thing!
I'll ask Auntie Qin for a solution.
They're lying.
Let's have some fun with them.
What do you mean?
These hicks all have simple minds.
They will definitely attempt a rescue.
We have our soldiers everywhere!
They wouldn't dare to.
I'll bring a few soldiers with me
and wipe them all out tomorrow.
Don't underestimate them.
No one can defeat me.
Certainly not hicks!
"THE GREAT RESCUE"
Listen up everyone.
These two stole from the Imperial Army.
In two hours they'll be taken away by train
to face judgment at the next station!
These two stole from the Imperial Army...
What're they doing?
In two hours
They want to see if anyone will rescue us
I hope our guys won't see us.
How do we stop them Brother?
We can't stop them.
Kites!
Pretty kites! Which one do you like?
What happened?
You Tigers...
You won't give up until you've gone too far.
Excuse me!
Wait!
Sir! Captain!
Please let me through.
I'm giving them some food!
What did they say?
They just want to give them food.
Let her through. Let her through!
It's you! Sneaking around again?
What is this?
Pancakes.
How dare you put our flag on them!
What flag? It's just a red dot!
That's our national flag!
It's just a red dot. It's auspicious!
The dot on your flag is bigger!
What did she say?
She says it's an auspicious pattern.
That's scallion.
I love the pancakes you make the most.
What did he say?
He says he really wants to eat these pancakes.
Please let them eat it!
Don't eat that. Give it to him!
I made it for him!
Tell them to leave.
Get out of here!
If your friends come to rescue you...
They'll all be captured
they'll all be captured.
If they don't
then they're not really your friends.
Then they're not really your friends.
The captain says that woman treats you well.
Auntie Qin is truly a great woman.
Shut up!
How much of the drug did you use?
Enough?
It ought to be.
I gave him a bigger dose than the donkey.
You're so greedy!
There are two pancakes.
You should give him one.
What did he say?
Nothing.
Tell him that it's delicious.
He really is a bit greedy.
Go!
Attention!
You are all excellent marksmen.
When the enemy approaches
fire on my order.
Wait for the order.
Don't fire until you hear it. Understand?
Yes sir!
They're all Japanese.
I'm sorry.
Load up and stand by!
Yes sir!
Captain they're here!
How many Japanese inside?
Sir! What do we do?
Captain!
Captain! Captain!
Don't move!
Please give the order to fire! Sir!
Fire!
Dakui!
Shut up!
Thank you all.
Good work Fan Chuan!
Are you one of us now?
Let's go!
Your little band here seems a bit... improper.
How are we improper?
We have hats like you do! Shut up!
I'll consider it.
No one knows this place. We'll hide here.
I didn't badmouth you! They were talking about
how the prisoner train was ambushed!
I know you have nothing to do with it!
I was just blending in with the crowd!
I didn't say you're one of them I swear!
Enough. Take this money.
What is this?
Auntie Qin will know.
Use this money to buy two pancakes.
No no no. I can't take your money...
Why're you standing there?!
I'm sorry!
Get out of here!
A thief.
Arrest him!
What's the point of hiding these worn clothes?
Fan Chuan. You in or out?
I'm in!
I'm with you all the way.
That's more like it!
Let's do it together! Let's go!
But I have one condition.
Now we're making conditions?
So you're a businessman!
Fan Chuan we have no money.
Say it!
Don't treat me like an outsider.
Hey I didn't mean it like that!
You ruthless shrew!
I really don't know anything... so painful!
Yuko!
I didn't see anything!
Stop! I'll talk! They're at Weishan Lake!
"The evening sun is setting in the west"
"Weishan Lake is peaceful and still"
"I will go..."
Brother your key is too low.
Mine isn't too low. His was high!
He was too low.
I think Brother was singing it pretty well.
You're clearly singing too low!
I'm too low?
Or maybe you're singing too high?
I started the song so I'm right.
He sang too low.
My Key's correct. Peaceful and still.
Brother's correct! But I set the key!
Then you set the wrong key!
Start it again.
The evening...
See? Too high!
Peaceful and still.
Brother! It's the Japanese!
How many bullets do we have left?
I can kill one man with each bullet...
Get down!
Give me the gun!
You want to fight your way out?
We can't do that now.
There's only one way out. Move.
They're gone...
(Japanese) Found them?
Hai!
Where are they? Hai!
Where are your guns?
Banzai!
Hurry!
Where are they?!
You idiot!
Hanzhuang Bridge is a major route.
The Japanese need it to send supplies
to the front line.
I think that's why the Eighth Route Army
wants to blow it up.
They want to cut their supplies.
Be careful Brother.
Fan Chuan. What's this called
in the Thirty-Six Stratagems?
"Taking the fuel."
It doesn't matter now.
The Eighth Route Army says the bridge
must be destroyed by tomorrow.
You haven't told us why you decided to join us.
Would you let people call you a coward?
Auntie Qin told me to bring him.
Huang gave it to me before he was arrested.
What's that traitor up to?
He asked me to buy pancakes from Auntie Qin.
I can't see it
What does it say?
A supply train is crossing
Hanzhuang Bridge tomorrow.
What does that mean?
Supply train... we have our explosives!
Can we trust that traitor's words?
That traitor sent the Japanese
to the island for us.
And now he let us go!
What is he up to?
It means he changes sides whenever it suits him.
I've met people like him.
But I believe him this time.
Either way this is our only chance.
Ask your spirits! Where are they hiding?
There'll be many Japanese soldiers
on that train tomorrow.
We're outnumbered.
We need more men.
I'll go!
Me too!
No not you.
O spirits of the earth and heavens...
something big is happening soon!
Ow that hurts!
My leg!
O heavenly spirits...
Great!
I've waited for this too long!
So we'll leave it to you?
Sure. Don't worry.
Listen everyone.
If we really manage to blow up the bridge tomorrow
we definitely won't make it back.
Do you understand me?
If anyone wants to back out
say it now.
Well?
Yes! Let's do it!
The Tigers aren't cowards!
We'd rather die than be slaves!
For our country!
We all have a duty!
Silence! Let Brother speak!
Brother how about a pep talk?
Right! Brother.
You should say something wise!
Shut up!
Eat up so you can fight the Japanese tomorrow.
And when you're done make it home alive for me...
and you can eat all the pancakes you want. Okay?
You hear me?
Say Brother.
Why do you carry that pipe with you?
He used to smoke but not anymore.
He misses the taste.
The truth is
years ago my father was smoking this pipe
when the Japanese shot him.
Later when my wife
was filling up the tobacco for me
she was killed by the Japanese.
I don't smoke now.
But I remember my grudge.
Dahai sing a song for us.
No way. They keep saying that I'm off-key.
You do go off-key...
I don't!
Nevermind.
What's the plan tomorrow?
Well.
Tomorrow when the train leaves Shagou Station
we hop aboard.
First find the explosives.
They should be in a closed cargo hold.
The Japanese will inspect
the train at Zaozhuang Station.
We'll hide making our move as the train leaves!
The train mustn't stop under any circumstance.
We'll stop the train
in the middle of the bridge.
Wrap the explosives around the bridge pillars.
When they explode the bridge will collapse.
You understand?
But what will happen to you?
Duang! Into the air. Mission accomplished.
Dad!
Why're you here?
I have to be there with you all!
Get off the train before we blow the bridge.
Fine!
Give me that!
Blow it!
Let's go!
Out of the way! Sir! I can't move them!
I'm sorry sir!
Cargo holds front and back.
Who's going to check them?
I'll check the back.
I'll bet that they're in the front. I'll go.
Go to the back.
You're clumsy. I'll check the front.
Zhu you stand guard.
I'll take the cab.
The rest of you hide.
Wait till we leave the station.
Let's go!
"BLOWING UP THE BRIDGE"
Attention!
Sir! Your orders?
Who said the explosives would be here?
Sit down!
Go ahead sir!
Rock paper scissors!
Again! Rock paper scissors!
Sit down!
Be seated!
Rock paper scissors!
Why are you crying?
I'm so moved but bad things happen when I smile.
Everything good?
Everything's fine sir
Are you sure?
Of course. If not I'll commit seppuku.
That's gonna hurt!
This is no time for jokes!
Open the door.
Stand up!
What are you wearing underneath?
Same as you.
I'm serious.
Close the door.
Close the door!
Raise your hands!
What's going on here sir?
She was being rude.
He's a fraud.
Fire!
Where's Yuko?
She's still on the train!
Give me a smile.
Don't move!
Hey!
Give me a smile.
There it is!
I told you not to move!
Don't move! I'll shoot anyone that moves!
I'll shoot anyone that moves!
Squad engage!
If you hadn't come
I could've shown them my shooting skills!
Where are you going?
Fire!
Don't push!
Got the explosives?
Zhu. Get on top of the last carriages!
Don't let them attack.
- Everyone...
- Watch out!
Everyone what?
I've forgotten
Block the side door Brother. Don't let them out.
You go help Sanlaizi.
Okay.
The rest of you help me with the cannon.
I don't know how to fire a cannon!
I do! Where's the ammo?
Over there under that cloth. Go!
I have bullets in my bag. Get them!
December moon what flowers will you bloom!
December flowers will bloom...
You almost hit me!
Hurry! Dad I'm useful right?
Shut up! Hurry!
Come help us Brother!
I'm busy too!
Where should I put this?
Blow them away!
Place it aside. Don't rush!
What are you doing?
I'm aiming!
Lift the cannon.
One two three! Go!
Wait! What are you doing?
Push it! Good! One two three!
This isn't the proper way!
We've never done things the proper way! Push!
Fire!
What? Fire!
Get away!
Pull!
How? Pull it back hard!
What is going on?!
That was a pretty good idea right?
This was definitely not proper...
Again! Yes!
Fire again. I'll help the others.
And me?
Keep covering your ears.
Be careful.
You got explosives there?
A lot!
Set one off!
Sure!
Fire in the hole!
Watch out!
Get away!
That really hurts...
Damn it!
Alright you wanna play?
It's those hicks!
Guys leave it to me!
Blow him away!
I may have lost to you years ago...
You hicks!
But I'll get you today!
Let's go!
Watch out!
That really hurts!
Dakui!
Are you hurt?
How many of these do we have to tie up?
The more the better!
I'll pay you back some day.
Shut up!
It hurts!
Don't let the train stop Rui!
Dahai don't you think that Xing'er likes me?
Where did that come from?
The train can't stop! The train can't stop!
This is too easy it's boring.
Come on!
I'll show you what a proper soldier...
can do!
Let's go! Good work!
What's that?
Fan Chuan.
Look what we found!
Quick! Give it to me!
Brother the boiler is leaking!
Dakui!
Zhuzi's fallen off the train!
Surrender!
What are they saying?
They're asking us to surrender.
I'll shoot the one talking. You take the other.
Wait that's too risky.
He's right behind Xing'er
Aren't you a sharpshooter?
No sharpshooter can curve a bullet!
Come back Dahai!
I'm coming Xing'er!
Xing'er! Stay back!
Dahai! Come back here too Sanlaizi!
Just listen to me and stay over there!
A tiger? Are there wings on that?
What'll we do?
I don't have any experience with this.
Run Xing'er!
Just leave them to me!
Everyone back off!
Dad I'm not afraid!
It's okay it's okay.
Time to go. You promised.
I want to be with you all until the very end!
We'll be back soon.
Dad!
Xing'er.
Come.
What are you doing?
Roll.
Roll!
Don't let her go!
The boiler's leaking.
We might not make it to the bridge.
Get your weapons boys!
Let's go!
Brother the train is stopping.
We've nowhere to retreat.
We'll fight them!
Let's go!
One two three now!
Retreat!
This rifle is no fun.
Wanna try this one? Okay!
This is awesome!
Dahai!
Someone's joining the party.
I'm back you hicks!
Just watch me. I'll blow him away with the tank.
What do we do now?
We still have our cannon.
Now what?
You want to beat me?
This is bad. We're running out of ammo.
It hasn't blown up yet? No way.
Rui!
Aren't the explosives over there?
We'll each take one pack and charge at them.
Then maybe...
It's useless. We won't make it past them.
But we're so close!
Looks like our big mission is set to fail.
I started this mission
so I'll see this through to the end.
You guys still have a chance to flee.
Shut up!
You're not the only member in the Tigers!
None of us are running!
We may not be proper soldiers
but we do just fine against the Japanese!
Tell us what to do!
Let's go!
I don't think we can take them head on.
How does it go in the Thirty-Six Stratagems?
How would I know which one you're talking about!
Hide. Let's hide!
You'll never beat me. Not in a million years!
Switch the tracks!
I'll block the train!
Got it!
What are you doing? Your dad said don't let go!
Let me go!
You got a death wish?
Search the train!
I speak Chinese!
I'll say it clearly this time
You have two choices.
One: I knock you both out with this.
Or two...
Zhuzi!
Who's on the train?
Put your backs into it!
It won't budge!
Dakui?
Why are we pulling that? Shut up!
Hide! Hurry!
Why won't you go away?!
Can't stop it now.
What is he doing?
We've got nothing sir!
Found them?
No sir!
Search again!
Yes sir!
Retreat! Retreat!
Retreat!
Don't move!
You hicks!
Retreat!
Let's go!
Brother!
Who's driving that train?
It must be Rui.
We three are the only ones left!
Keep them back.
I'm going to set off the explosives!
Hurry! We can't hold them off for long!
Brother!
Shut up!
We can't hold them any longer!
Why won't that Japanese devil die!
I have you now.
Are you going to shoot or what?
Can you do this?
They're too close. I'll hit both of them.
Hold your fire!
I'll get him myself!
Brother it looks like
our big mission has failed!
I'm sorry I couldn't hold them off!
We've failed Daguo
and the Eighth Route Army!
We'll start with you.
What's going on?!
Charge!
Fire! Kill them all!
Go all of you!
Kill them all!
All of you go!
Don't worry about those guys...
I can handle them myself.
I'll kill you!
That hurts!
Charge!
You hicks...
Tiger. Come on it's time to go.
Can this be our secret?
Sure no problem
Did they all go to heaven?
Actually...
they all joined the Eighth Route Army afterwards
and protected our country.
What about the injured soldier?
Did he go to heaven?
That's another story. Do you want to hear it?
Yeah!
Okay I'll tell you.
Sorry sorry my hat fell off.
Hit me? You hit me?!
I forgot my lines... Sorry
Running around... And I... I...
I'm Dahai he's Daguo and you are?
Rm Daguo!
What's your character's name?
I'm Dahai he's Daguo...
What's your name?
I'm Ma Yun... Ma Yuan
Again. I almost fell off!
I almost...
You want me to do it again?
Sorry sorry...
I don't know how to draw it!
It's so cold that I can't speak. Again!
...there are no Howards.
Cowards!
You said your mother killed you!
Wait I sang the wrong song!
The evening... I've forgotten.
The evening sun...
The evening sun is setting in the west!
What lake?
Weishan Lake! Again!
They're at Weishan Lake!